<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Human Boring</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Human Boring</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-GB</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Nov 2015 18:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Privalige</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2015-11-08-Privalige/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Nov 2015 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2015-11-08-Privalige/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Often, people aren&amp;rsquo;t aware of the invisible advantages they have in life, especially when they&amp;rsquo;re white men. This was me for quite a while (and now I&amp;rsquo;m still unaware to an extent).  I have, however, become more aware of the privileges I have in life. Weirdly, my journey to awareness started on Reddit of all places.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spent much of my teenage years browsing the web, looking for ways to pass the time when I should have been studying or spending time outside. This time-wasting was also how I met my significant other, but that&amp;rsquo;s another story. As a web forum with very little moderation, Reddit inevitably is home to some of the worst aspects of human interaction. Sexism, racism, homophobia and more is common, often presented as a &amp;lsquo;joke&amp;rsquo;. There&amp;rsquo;s a reason that &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.salon.com/2015/03/18/reddits_ugly_racist_secret_how_it_became_the_most_hateful_space_on_the_internet/&#34;&gt;Stormfront and Reddit users have a big overlap&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How reddit works, if you are unaware, is that anybody can post a topic to the site, onto one of the many (mainly user-created) subsections known as &amp;lsquo;subreddits, and then anybody can post a comment on these links. The additional feature of reddit is that people can vote comments and links up or down, and those with the highest gross vote rise to the top. One subreddit that I stumbled upon the website is known as &lt;a href=&#34;ww.reddit.com/r/shitredditsays/&#34;&gt;&amp;lsquo;Shit Reddit Says&amp;rsquo;&lt;/a&gt;, which is dedicated to finding and pointing out the awful comments posted on Reddit with positive votes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I first visited this page, I started seeing some of the most awful things other people were posting online. Sexism, racism, homophobia, transphobia - pretty much any bigotry you can imagine was there. The worst thing is, not only did individuals believe the things they were posting, but often hundreds or even thousands of people thought that these comments were good and worth sharing with others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seeing some of the worst of humanity (including child-porn apologists and supporters) was a wake-up for me. From this starting point, I make a conscious effort to educate myself. Following the advice of &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/siracusa&#34;&gt;John Siracusa&lt;/a&gt;, I made a point of following many more women, people of colour, and LGBTQ+ people on twitter&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:98e7f6fdd482aa6021c4b32df07fb368:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:98e7f6fdd482aa6021c4b32df07fb368:1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, and just read what they have to say. Although I am clearly far from perfect, I am trying to be aware of the advantages I have &amp;ldquo;playing life on &lt;a href=&#34;http://kotaku.com/5910857/straight-white-male-the-lowest-difficulty-setting-there-is&#34;&gt;easy mode&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:98e7f6fdd482aa6021c4b32df07fb368:1&#34;&gt;Foxes are red
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:98e7f6fdd482aa6021c4b32df07fb368:1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;[return]&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ad-blocking on iOS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2015-10-02-Ad-Blocking-on-iOS/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2015 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2015-10-02-Ad-Blocking-on-iOS/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With iOS 9, it became possible to install apps that allow you to block all ads on the internet (but unfortunately not in apps). However, since it&amp;rsquo;s not totally simple to enable them, I made a quick guide, with screenshots.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, go to the app store and find your ad-blocker app. I&amp;rsquo;m using one called &lt;a href=&#34;http://cocoaapp.com/adamant/&#34;&gt;Adamant&lt;/a&gt; in the screenshots, but it&amp;rsquo;s the same process for any app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://cloud.githubusercontent.com/assets/13935212/10263073/1804ec64-69d8-11e5-9a42-2c56a4875650.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Step 1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once the app is downloaded, you&amp;rsquo;ll need to exit to the homescreen and go to the settings page. Scroll until you find the section labled &amp;lsquo;Safari&amp;rsquo;, and tap on that. In that screen, there should be an option labled &amp;lsquo;Content Blockers&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://cloud.githubusercontent.com/assets/13935212/10263071/180416d6-69d8-11e5-8ece-84a475fa97c1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Step 2&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you&amp;rsquo;ve tapped on the &amp;lsquo;Content Blockers&amp;rsquo; lable, you should see the app you downloaded listed. Make sure to flick the switch next to it&amp;rsquo;s name to the green &amp;lsquo;on&amp;rsquo; position.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://cloud.githubusercontent.com/assets/13935212/10263069/1803adea-69d8-11e5-9d42-bef99d582125.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Step 3&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some ad-blocker apps might have some settings in the app that you can interact with, and others (like Adamant), are just ready to go at this point. Now you won&amp;rsquo;t see any ads in safari, and should save data ad battery life &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2015/10/01/business/cost-of-mobile-ads.html?_r=0&#34;&gt;while you&amp;rsquo;re at it&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How not to fix the Apple Watch</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2015-09-26-How-not-to-fix-apple-watch/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Sep 2015 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2015-09-26-How-not-to-fix-apple-watch/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;David Pogue (relatively) recently made a post on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.yahoo.com/tech/a-humble-proposition-how-to-fix-the-apple-watch-129185196924.html&#34;&gt;how to fix the Apple Watch&lt;/a&gt;. Now, I’ll fully agree that the Apple Watch isn’t a perfect product - what is? - but theres a few things in the article I take issue with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s the central problem: Apple went overboard with input mechanisms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How many ways are there to navigate using a phone’s touchscreen? Four: tap, swipe, tap-and-hold, or pinch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But on the Apple Watch, there are seven navigation tools: Turn the crown (the knob on the side). Click the crown inward. Tap the side button. Hold in the side button. Tap the screen. Hard-press the screen. Swipe across the screen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re going to include all the different buttons for navigation, then on the iPhone side you really need to include the home button. In this method of counting that’s another three (tap, hold, and double-tap). On the 6S we also now have 3D touch with two levels, but in Pogue’s defence that wasn’t announced at the time the article was written.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re counting, we’re up to a total of 7 for the iPhone (9 for 6s), and 8 for the watch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He goes on to explain his problems with the spacial navigation, and offer a solution to this.&lt;br /&gt;
Image below credit &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.yahoo.com/tech/a-humble-proposition-how-to-fix-the-apple-watch-129185196924.html&#34;&gt;Pogue/Yahoo&lt;/a&gt; .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://cloud.githubusercontent.com/assets/13935212/10263072/1804bae6-69d8-11e5-834e-f277fb03c6c3.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Why are you reading this?&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At first glance, this proposal seems to make sense, however with more thought some problems appear. Scroll up to the notifications. Now you can scroll left or right. So which way to the newest alerts? Which way to the oldest? Why have I just jumped up to somewhere in the middle of my notification timeline?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ok, back to the watch face. Now if you were to scroll left to the home screen. Now scroll again to the friends screen. Wait, did you swipe across screens, or did you scroll around the home screen?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now you’ve made it to the friends screen you can go left to some running apps. And you can go right, past the watch face to some apps. Which ones are on which side? Why? Who knows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess the point of this is it’s easy to say things are confusing or need improving, but playing amateur designer isn’t easy. I for sure couldn’t make a better watch, and there’s a reason designer is a paid job.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Takashi Yasui</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2015-08-26-Takashi-Yasui/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2015 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2015-08-26-Takashi-Yasui/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This photographer from Kyoto takes some amazing photos that really caught my eye. Definitely worth checking them out and following them on &lt;a href=&#34;https://instagram.com/_tuck4/&#34;&gt;Instagram&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://cloud.githubusercontent.com/assets/13935212/10263067/17dbc8fc-69d8-11e5-9830-bac2b1631c45.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Fushimi Inari-taisha&#34; /&gt;
Credit: Takashi Yasui&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Via &lt;a href=&#34;http://abduzeedo.com/street-photography-japan-takashi-yasui&#34;&gt;Abduzeebo&lt;/a&gt; (Check out their page for a selection of some more of Takashi&amp;rsquo;s photos)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>San Fransisco</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2015-08-24-San-Fransisco/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2015 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2015-08-24-San-Fransisco/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/180b91c2-69d8-11e5-9b43-f32401409eb7.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;SF House&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was my first time visiting the city, and only second time in the US, and I enjoyed nearly every minute of it. San Fransisco is a lovely city to visit (though not sure about live in because of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://sf.curbed.com/archives/2015/05/22/san_franciscos_median_rent_climbs_to_a_whopping_4225.php&#34;&gt;ridiculous rent cost&lt;/a&gt; ).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The many hills in the city offer amazing views. One day I climbed up to Coit Tower, which offers some of the best vistas in the city.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/17f29fdc-69d8-11e5-824d-87cd45c9de98.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Coit views&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also enjoyed some of the amazing coffee from &lt;a href=&#34;https://bluebottlecoffee.com&#34;&gt;Blue Bottle&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sightglasscoffee.com&#34;&gt;Sightglass&lt;/a&gt;, a boat trip round the bay, walking through the various parts of the city, and using Uber for the first time. I particularly recommend visiting Clarion Alley if you have the chance. They have a &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Clarion_Alley_Mural_Project&#34;&gt;mural project&lt;/a&gt;, where artists are invited to paint murals all along the walls of the alley.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/18215462-69d8-11e5-995e-0d2bc9f5f85c.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Clarion Alley&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took dozens of pictures of the murals down that alley. All round the mission there are other buildings and streets with murals painted on them, some of them historically and culturally important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in all, it&amp;rsquo;s a city that&amp;rsquo;s well worth a visit if you get a chance.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>366</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2016-01-01-366-Days/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2016-01-01-366-Days/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;1-366:b334a73f238b284362b6886cb60f1ee7&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;366&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today is the first day of the new year. My resolution to myself was to be more active on my blog, since I went through all the trouble of getting it up and running. However, I&amp;rsquo;m not somebody to whom being active online comes easy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The solution came when I was browsing the web, as it so often does. I stumbled across the &lt;a href=&#34;http://2016photochallenge.com&#34;&gt;Pic: 366&lt;/a&gt; site, where people are encouraged to post one photo per day of 2016 online. For me, this website will be my location.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;366&lt;/sub&gt; - View from my old bedroom in my parent&amp;rsquo;s house.
&lt;img src=&#34;https://images.typed.com/ef8dcb76-2e4c-4b0c-8e73-4b3ab8dbedc2/IMG_0118.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;1/366&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>